Personal Email dsaavedra10120 outlook.com Phone Number (520) 403-8550

Address 7940 N Paul Revere Pl Tucson, AZ 85742

Armando Saavedra

Data Scientist

Professional Summary Data analyst and economist with experience designing and applying quantitative algorithms to predict or classify different sorts of information. The methods applied in my portfolio are: time series analysis, neural networks, knn clustering, multinomial logistic regression. I also have experience using Python, Rstudio and SQL.

Education

2018 - 2020, University of Arizona

Master of Sciecne in Information Science

2019 - 2019, DataCamp

Data Science with R Track

2007 - 2012, Catholic University of Colombia

Bachelor of Science in Economics

Experience

December 2019 - Present, Data Scientist, Pima Community College

Detailed achievements:

- Use of machine learning models to predict academic behavior:
- · Prepare reports about institutional performance.

August 2011 - January 2014, Junior Economist, Fedegan

Detailed achievements:

- Use of time series analysis to predict monthly price in male cattle premiums. Where the follow methods were applied:
 - Autoregressive Models -VAR
 - AutoRegressive Integrated Moving Average -ARIMA
- Structured a methodological framework for transferring production knowledge to different cattle associations.

May 2010 - August 2011, Teller, BCSC Bank, Buy More

Teller for several offices of the bank where I employed functions as:

- Teller operations
- Selling Financial Products
- · Customer Service

Projects

2015, Oral Presentation, California Business Conference

Presented research I conducted for my Masters of Engineering degree.

2014, Poster, Annual Business Conference (Oregon)

As part of the course work for BUS320, I created a poster analyzing several local businesses and presented this at a conference.

Software Development Skills

Programming

- PythonRSQL
- Power BI
 HTML/CSS
 SAP Web Reports

Interests

Professional

Data analysis, statistical computing, risk analysis, economics, web design, finance, operation research